In a time of war, they found themselves in the most
dangerous place of all. In love.
Bent is a drama, history, romance film directed by Sean Mathias.
Max is a handsome young man who, after a fateful tryst with a
German soldier, is forced to run for his life.
Eventually Max is placed in a concentration camp where he pretends to be Jewish
because in the eyes of the Nazis, gays are the lowest form of human being.
But it takes a relationship with an openly gay prisoner to teach Max that
without the love of another, life is not worth living.
Horst, played by Lothaire Bluteau.
Max, played by Clive Owen.
Rudy, played by Brian Webber.
Uncle Freddie, played by Ian McKellen.
Greta / George, played by Mick Jagger.
Captain, played by Paul Bettany.
Bent is a 1997 drama film directed by Sean Mathias, based on the 1979 play of
the same name by Martin Sherman, who also wrote the screenplay.
It revolves around the persecution of homosexuals in Nazi Germany after the
murder of SA leader Ernst Röhm on the Night of the Long Knives.
The film explores themes of nazi, concentration camp
prisoner, based on play or musical, gay theme.
The tone is emotional.